<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ux on drew:ux</title>
    <link>http://drewux.com/tags/ux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ux on drew:ux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://drewux.com/tags/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Embracing White Space: Why Less Is More in UX Design</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/embracing-white-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/embracing-white-space/</guid>
      <description>Embracing White Space Why Less Is More in UX Design 3 minute read You&amp;rsquo;ve been there: you&amp;rsquo;re presenting a sleek, functional user interface to stakeholders, only to have them request that you cram more information into the available space. Sound familiar? As UX designers, we often face the challenge of convincing stakeholders that white space is not wasted space, but rather a crucial element for creating an efficient, user-friendly experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Power of ChatGPT to Supercharge Your UX Workflow</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/ten-chatgpt-prompts-to-supercharge-your-ux-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/ten-chatgpt-prompts-to-supercharge-your-ux-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Harnessing the Power of ChatGPT to Supercharge Your UX Workflow Ten Powerful ChatGPT Prompts to Incorporate into Your Design Process 10 minute read The world of UX design is ever-evolving, and staying ahead of the curve can be a challenging task. But what if I told you that AI-powered chatbots like ChatGPT can help streamline your UX workflow and provide valuable insights? That&amp;rsquo;s right! In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore 10 prompts that UX practitioners can give ChatGPT to improve their workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can ChatGPT Optimize Your Website&#39;s UX? Let&#39;s Find Out</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/can-chatgpt-optimize-your-websites-ux-lets-find-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/can-chatgpt-optimize-your-websites-ux-lets-find-out/</guid>
      <description>Can ChatGPT Optimize Your Website&amp;rsquo;s UX? Let&amp;rsquo;s Find Out Using AI to analyze webpages and provide UX recommendations 3 minute read TL;DR: Nope. Failure to launch. But other tools may provide better results.
Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing various industries, and the field of user experience (UX) is no exception. As AI-powered tools like ChatGPT become more sophisticated, we can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if they can offer valuable insights to improve our webpages&amp;rsquo; UX, accessibility, and performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five AI Tools UX Researchers Should Be Using to Improve Their Work and Efficiency</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/top-5-ai-tools-ux-researchers-should-be-using-to-improve-their-work-and-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/top-5-ai-tools-ux-researchers-should-be-using-to-improve-their-work-and-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Five AI Tools UX Researchers Should Be Using to Improve Their Work and Efficiency Innovative AI-powered tools to try out UX researchers, it&amp;rsquo;s time to embrace the future! As AI continues to advance and integrate into various aspects of our lives, it&amp;rsquo;s essential for us to keep up with the game. Today, I want to share with you five AI-powered tools that will not only enhance your research efforts but also boost your efficiency in the UX field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging AI to Extract Customer Personas from Real-Life Interviews</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/leveraging-ai-to-extract-customer-personas-from-real-life-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/leveraging-ai-to-extract-customer-personas-from-real-life-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Leveraging AI to Extract Customer Personas from Real-Life Interviews An Experiment with ChatGPT-4 10 minute read Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the use of ChatGPT-4 to analyze and extract customer personas from real-life interview data. By using AI, researchers can save significant time by avoiding manual analysis of lengthy audio recordings. The quality is pretty good, but you need to pay attention to the overall accuracy of the output.
Introduction Discovering and understanding customer personas is a common activity for businesses to create user-centered strategies and cater to the needs of their audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX and AI: Tools to Streamline Your UX Workflow</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/ux-ai-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/ux-ai-tools/</guid>
      <description>UX and AI Tools to Streamline Your UX Workflow 5 minute read As UX professionals, we all know the importance of collecting and analyzing data to inform design decisions and improve the user experience. But with so much data to collect and analyze, it can be a time-consuming and overwhelming process. That&amp;rsquo;s where AI-powered tools come in. By using these tools, we can streamline our UX workflows, saving time and increasing efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean UX: The Ultimate Framework for Integrating UX and Agile Development</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/lean-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/lean-ux/</guid>
      <description>Lean UX: The Ultimate Framework for Integrating UX and Agile Development Delve into the Lean UX methodology, its components, and real-world success stories Discover how Lean UX bridges the gap between UX and Agile development, explore its components, and learn from real-world success stories and challenges in the era of remote work.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always been passionate about finding ways to seamlessly integrate UX and Agile development, and the Lean UX methodology has proven to be an ideal solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/front-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/front-matter/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Free Remote UX Tools to Boost Your Workflow</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/five-free-remote-ux-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/five-free-remote-ux-tools/</guid>
      <description>5 Free Remote UX Tools to Boost Your Workflow Discover budget-friendly solutions for remote UX research and collaboration 2 ½ minute read Hey there, fellow UX advocates! Working remotely can be challenging on its own, and even more difficult when you&amp;rsquo;re on a budget. Many of the most exciting and essential tools for conducting UX research and design come with heft monthly subscription costs. But don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ve got your back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling UX and Agile Development: A Unified Approach</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/reconciling-ux-and-agile-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/reconciling-ux-and-agile-development/</guid>
      <description>Reconciling UX and Agile Development: A Unified Approach Integrating UX Design into the Agile Process for Holistic, User-Centric Product Development 3 minute read Discover how to reconcile UX and Agile development by integrating UX design into the Agile process for a holistic, user-centric product development approach.
Welcome to my second installment focused on UX and Agile. Agile development has long been known for its programmer-centric approach, which can sometimes leave UX feeling like a &amp;ldquo;side process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrum, Kanban, and Scrumban: Integrating UX into Agile Methodologies</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/scrum-kanban-scrumban-and-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/scrum-kanban-scrumban-and-ux/</guid>
      <description>Scrum, Kanban, and Scrumban: Integrating UX into Agile Methodologies Explore the pros and cons of Scrum, Kanban, and hybrid approaches for UX practitioners in the Agile world A handful of years back, I found myself participating in a Scrum-focused Agile training with the aim of earning certification. Coming from a UX background, I couldn’t help but be plagued by a persistent concern: how on earth does UX fit into all of this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Business with Unicorns</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-10-29-unicorns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-10-29-unicorns/</guid>
      <description>This Business with Unicorns A Raccoon, a Panda, and a Unicorn walk into a bar 3 ½ minute read Unicorns: Mythical creatures that are spoken of, but never seen. In the UX world, the term is used to describe that rare person who can do it all — design, research, write, and code — and do it at a very high level. It&amp;rsquo;s become so common that companies looking for talent are putting out job ads for so-called &amp;ldquo;unicorns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnitude</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-10-16-magnitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-10-16-magnitude/</guid>
      <description>Magnitude A Simple Tool to Help Prioritize Usability Issues 6 minute read When prioritizing usability problems, use a Magnitude Matrix to figure out the most important issues to address. Magnitude combines the frequency that an issue was observed with the relative impact that it had on the participant&amp;rsquo;s task completion.
After spending some time revisiting best practices in the realm of usability testing and reviewing the advice of some its more esteemed practitioners, I realized that there is a lot of talk about how to go about setting up such a test, and finding usability problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playback</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-10-2-playback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-10-2-playback/</guid>
      <description>Playback Often the best way to fix your faults is to look directly at them 4 minute read Regularly reviewing your performance and providing self-critique can help you improve your skills as a usability test moderator.
The camera and microphone are powerful implements in a usability tester&amp;rsquo;s toolkit. With them, you can capture the user&amp;rsquo;s actions and facial expressions and gain all kinds of insight into their behaviors, thoughts and expectations when using a product.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Qualitative Data</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-24-reporting-qualitative-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-24-reporting-qualitative-data/</guid>
      <description>Reporting Qualitative Data Gaining Control of the Fuzzy Non-Numeric 3 minute read When dealing with moderate to large sets of qualitative data, affinity analysis can help identify and prioritize common issues that users experience.
We&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time discussing quantitative data this week: Collecting, measuring, and analyzing it. This got me thinking about its more nebulous twin — qualitative data — and how it&amp;rsquo;s a whole different beast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye-Tracking on the Cheap</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-17-eye-tracking-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-17-eye-tracking-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Eye-Tracking on the Cheap A Dead-Simple Way to Follow Your Test Participants 2 minute read In the absence of eye-tracking equipment, ask test participants to use their mouse cursor to indicate where they’re looking on the screen.
One of the hallmarks of usability testing protocols is [the “Think Aloud” method][1]: Asking participants to verbalize their thoughts as they work through the tasks and activities of the test. This method allows the test team to get inside the head of the participant a bit and often illuminates behaviors or attitudes that wouldn’t be apparent by observation alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formative vs. Summative Usability Studies</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-10-formative-summative-usability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-10-formative-summative-usability/</guid>
      <description>Staying Ahead of the Wave Formative vs. Summative Usability Studies 2 ½ minute read When looking at usability studies, you can generally lump them into two groups: Formative studies and summative studies. We&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about them this week and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a little bit about our approach.
Formative Studies Formative studies, as the name implies, tend to happen at the beginning of the design process and are used to help guide the product in the right direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote UX Observation</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-01-getting-out-of-the-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-09-01-getting-out-of-the-room/</guid>
      <description>Remote UX Observation Getting Out of the Room to Enhance Team Participation In UX 4 ½ minute read One of the major tenets we adhere to as a team is transparency: All members of the team should have access to information about the project we’re working on. Designers, Developers, QA Analysts, Stakeholders: They all should have a complete picture of what’s going on and access to any details of the project that might help them gain product perspective and user insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IxD Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-07-01-ixd-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-07-01-ixd-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>Retrospective Looking back on the Kent State Interaction Design class 4 minute read So another course in the Kent State University User Experience Design Masters program comes to an end and, as one of its requirements has been these weekly updates, I thought it would be a good idea to use the final one to look back on the class.
I’ve spent the last seven weeks diving into Interaction Design; looking into the design process for digital products from the user interface perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Twice, Cut Once</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-19-mobile-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-19-mobile-layouts/</guid>
      <description>Measure Twice, Cut Once Creating a reusable layout system for mobile 4 ½ minute read So, while slugging it out in the trenches this week, I sort of fell into an existential crisis with regards to the stuff I was putting on the screen for a mobile prototype. Panels, images, buttons, text fields&amp;hellip; the sizing and positioning of these things all suddenly seemed so arbitrary. How can you defend a design decision if you can&amp;rsquo;t explain why the thing on the screen looks like it does?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critique</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-12-critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-12-critique/</guid>
      <description>Critique When having your back means shooting you down 5 minute read I’ve got a good team.
I know this not because my team is talented; not because they wield terrifying text editors and pixel manipulators with the deftness of a Mayo Clinic surgeon (although they most certainly do). I know this because they are good at critique.
They are able to look at something — a design, concept, prototype — with a critical eye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InVision This</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-05-invision-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-05-invision-this/</guid>
      <description>InVision This Much more than fancy screenshots 2 ½ minute read As you’ve probably gathered if you’ve been following along, I spend a lot of time talking about tools. Too much, probably. Tools, after all, don’t make the craftsman. But, here I go again: After a couple of weeks using InVision.app for a project of some complexity, I have to say. Wow.
I’ve been aware of InVision for awhile, but always thought of it as a fancy presentation tool (which it is) and nothing more (which it isn’t).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fidelity</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-05-29-fidelity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-05-29-fidelity/</guid>
      <description>Fidelity When making wireframes, aim somewhere between hi-fi and lo-fi 4 minute read We spent a lot of time this week discussing fidelity as it pertains to UX deliverables: Wireframes in this case. The traditional wisdom has always been that wireframes are quick and dirty interface representations, stripped of any visual design or branding elements. Their purpose is to communicate the general layout and content of a page without getting too deep into the visual design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Tools</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-05-22-know-your-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-05-22-know-your-tools/</guid>
      <description>Know your tools Investing time creating a basic toolkit early can really pay off 2 minute read Which design tools you use are far less important than how well you can use them. This became especially apparent after weeks of using a template I created for the last class. It was easy. The bugs were ironed out. It looked okay. It didn&amp;rsquo;t win me any points for creative vision but it was fast and got the job done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Yin and Yang: Balancing Organizational Goals and the Needs of Your Users</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2015-12-08-ux-yin-yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2015-12-08-ux-yin-yang/</guid>
      <description>UX Yin and Yang Balancing Organizational Goals and the Needs of Your Users 4½ minute read The disciplines of user-centered design have taught us to go to great lengths to ensure that we meet the needs of users when it comes to our products, but we shouldn’t be doing so at the expense of the organization’s goals.
Call it a lesson learned. Awhile back my buddy (whom I&amp;rsquo;ll call &amp;ldquo;Ted,&amp;rdquo; in an attempt to spare his identity) completed a project that he’d spent significant time designing and building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them):  Part 2, Management</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2015-11-19-content-challenges-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2015-11-19-content-challenges-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them) Part 2 — Challenges for Management 3½ minute read Last week I discussed the five most common content strategy challenges for content creators and strategists. Organizational leadership faces a similar predicament. With so much emphasis put on productivity, efficiency and the bottom line, it’s hard to embrace a concept that doesn’t show a clear benefit for the organization, introduces too much risk or just doesn’t fit in with their vision of the company and its values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them):  Part 1, The Content Creator</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2015-11-10-content-challenges-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2015-11-10-content-challenges-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them) Part 1 — The Content Creator 3½ minute read Content strategy is an important component of the design process and vital to the overall user experience. It ensures that the organization’s content aligns with its goals and values. With that in mind, here are ten key challenges that content creators and management face with content strategy, and some proposed solutions.
Challenges for Content Creators Content creators and strategists have it rough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The UX Triple Constraint: Time, Complexity and the User Experience</title>
      <link>http://drewux.com/posts/2014-06-25-the-ux-triple-constraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2014-06-25-the-ux-triple-constraint/</guid>
      <description>The UX Triple-Constraint Time, Complexity and the User Experience 4 minute read Someone much smarter than I has probably already made this observation, but it occurred to me in a recent discussion with a product stakeholder that there exists a kind of “usability triple constraint,” not too different from the one folks in the project management world have recognized for years.
The triple constraint is a project management model that says that all projects are a balance of time, resources, and quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
