<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>design on drew:ux</title><link>http://drewux.com/tags/design/</link><description>Recent content in design on drew:ux</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://drewux.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IxD Retrospective</title><link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-07-01-ixd-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-07-01-ixd-retrospective/</guid><description>Retrospective Looking back on the Kent State Interaction Design class 4 minute read So another course in the Kent State University User Experience Design Masters program comes to an end and, as one of its requirements has been these weekly updates, I thought it would be a good idea to use the final one to look back on the class.
I’ve spent the last seven weeks diving into Interaction Design; looking into the design process for digital products from the user interface perspective.</description></item><item><title>Organized</title><link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-26-organized/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-26-organized/</guid><description>Organized The extra time taken to arrange your work is a true sign of professionalism 2½ minute read Look. What your workspace looks like when you go home for the day is your business. It’s your space and you need to be comfortable and able to get stuff done. Maybe it’s a minimalist nirvana; clean and cool and white. Maybe it’s a nest of papers, books, half-empty soda cans… whatever works for you.</description></item><item><title>Measure Twice, Cut Once</title><link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-19-mobile-layouts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-19-mobile-layouts/</guid><description>Measure Twice, Cut Once Creating a reusable layout system for mobile 4 ½ minute read So, while slugging it out in the trenches this week, I sort of fell into an existential crisis with regards to the stuff I was putting on the screen for a mobile prototype. Panels, images, buttons, text fields&amp;hellip; the sizing and positioning of these things all suddenly seemed so arbitrary. How can you defend a design decision if you can&amp;rsquo;t explain why the thing on the screen looks like it does?</description></item><item><title>Critique</title><link>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-12-critique/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://drewux.com/posts/2016-06-12-critique/</guid><description>Critique When having your back means shooting you down 5 minute read I’ve got a good team.
I know this not because my team is talented; not because they wield terrifying text editors and pixel manipulators with the deftness of a Mayo Clinic surgeon (although they most certainly do). I know this because they are good at critique.
They are able to look at something — a design, concept, prototype — with a critical eye.</description></item></channel></rss>