<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on drew:ux</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on drew:ux</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Accessible Content and Media: Crafting Inclusivity in Digital Communication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/accessible-content-and-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/accessible-content-and-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;accessible-content-and-media&#34;&gt;Accessible Content and Media&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;crafting-inclusivity-in-digital-communication&#34;&gt;Crafting Inclusivity in Digital Communication&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-minute-read&#34;&gt;7 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our continuing series on web accessibility. Today, we turn our lens to a crucial aspect that often shapes the first impression of any digital platform: Content and Media. Accessibility in this realm isn&amp;rsquo;t just a compliance checkbox; it&amp;rsquo;s a commitment to inclusivity that opens doors for all users, regardless of their abilities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing-accessible-web-content&#34;&gt;Writing Accessible Web Content&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Creating content that&amp;rsquo;s accessible to a broad audience means ensuring it&amp;rsquo;s understandable by everyone, regardless of their educational background, age, or cognitive ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Accessibility: Mastering Keyboard-Friendly Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/navigating-accessibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/navigating-accessibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigating-accessibility&#34;&gt;Navigating Accessibility&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mastering-keyboard-friendly-design&#34;&gt;Mastering Keyboard-Friendly Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-minute-read&#34;&gt;8 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Keyboard navigation is essential for many users, including those with motor disabilities, temporary injuries, or a preference for keyboard use. It involves more than tabbing through links; it&amp;rsquo;s about ensuring all interactive elements are accessible without a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our deep dive into web accessibility. After exploring color and contrast, we now focus on a vital yet often overlooked aspect: keyboard navigation. While primarily aimed at users with motor disabilities; it&amp;rsquo;s for anyone who relies on a keyboard to navigate the web. This could include people with temporary disabilities (being forced, for instance, to use their non-dominant hand due to an injury), or a power-user who prefers to do as much navigating via the keyboard as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Color and Contrast: Crafting Visually Accessible Websites</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/color-and-contrast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/color-and-contrast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;color-and-contrast&#34;&gt;Color and Contrast&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;crafting-visually-accessible-websites&#34;&gt;Crafting Visually Accessible Websites&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-minute-read&#34;&gt;3 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Color and contrast are powerful tools in conveying meaning, function, and emotion on websites and applications. However, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to recognize that these elements are perceived differently by individuals, impacting their experience with them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to our series on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/accessibility/&#34;&gt;designing accessible websites&lt;/a&gt;. Having laid the groundwork on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/starting-with-accessibility-in-mind/&#34;&gt;accessibility basics and team roles&lt;/a&gt;, let&amp;rsquo;s turn our attention to a crucial, yet often overlooked, aspect of accessible design — color and contrast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting with Accessibility in Mind: Building Inclusive Web Experiences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/starting-with-accessibility-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/starting-with-accessibility-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;starting-with-accessibility-in-mind&#34;&gt;Starting with Accessibility in Mind&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-inclusive-web-experiences&#34;&gt;Building Inclusive Web Experiences&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-minute-read&#34;&gt;5 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the second in a series of articles looking into the requirements, tools, and techniques surrounding &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/accessibility&#34;&gt;accessible web design&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the journey of creating accessible web design, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to start with a foundation that prioritizes accessibility from the outset. This second article in our series dives into how you can embed an accessibility-first mindset in your web projects from the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Web Accessibility: A Foundation for Inclusive Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/understanding-web-accessibility-foundation-inclusive-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/understanding-web-accessibility-foundation-inclusive-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-web-accessibility&#34;&gt;Understanding Web Accessibility&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-foundation-for-inclusive-design&#34;&gt;A Foundation for Inclusive Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;25-minute-read&#34;&gt;2.5 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first in a series of articles looking into the requirements, tools, and techniques surrounding accessible web design&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the digital world, there&amp;rsquo;s a crucial aspect of website design that often flies under the radar, especially for those new to the concept: accessibility. It&amp;rsquo;s about ensuring your website is usable by everyone, which includes people with disabilities. But accessibility isn&amp;rsquo;t just for a select few; it&amp;rsquo;s a practice that benefits all users, in all kinds of situations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embracing White Space: Why Less Is More in UX Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/embracing-white-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/embracing-white-space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;embracing-white-space&#34;&gt;Embracing White Space&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-less-is-more-in-ux-design&#34;&gt;Why Less Is More in UX Design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-minute-read&#34;&gt;3 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is a challenge all designers have faced at one time or another: Convincing a stakeholder or product owner that white space is not wasted space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s a situation familiar to many designers: you’ve crafted a sleek, functional user interface only to have stakeholders ask you to add &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; — more options, more content, more graphics. Sound familiar? For UX designers, it&amp;rsquo;s a common challenge to demonstrate that white space is not wasted space, but rather a critical element for creating an efficient, user-friendly experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can ChatGPT Optimize Your Website&#39;s UX? Let&#39;s Find Out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-chatgpt-optimize-your-websites-ux-lets-find-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/can-chatgpt-optimize-your-websites-ux-lets-find-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;can-chatgpt-optimize-your-websites-ux-lets-find-out&#34;&gt;Can ChatGPT Optimize Your Website&amp;rsquo;s UX? Let&amp;rsquo;s Find Out&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-ai-to-analyze-webpages-and-provide-ux-recommendations&#34;&gt;Using AI to analyze webpages and provide UX recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-minute-read&#34;&gt;3 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: Nope. Failure to launch. But other tools may provide better results.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) is revolutionizing various industries, and the field of user experience (UX) is no exception. As AI-powered tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://chat.openai.com/&#34;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt; become more sophisticated, we can&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if they can offer valuable insights to improve our webpages&amp;rsquo; UX, accessibility, and performance. So, we decided to put ChatGPT to the test and see if it can analyze a webpage&amp;rsquo;s HTML and CSS code and provide specific recommendations. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into our experiment!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging AI to Extract Customer Personas from Real-Life Interviews</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leveraging-ai-to-extract-customer-personas-from-real-life-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leveraging-ai-to-extract-customer-personas-from-real-life-interviews/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;leveraging-ai-to-extract-customer-personas-from-real-life-interviews&#34;&gt;Leveraging AI to Extract Customer Personas from Real-Life Interviews&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-experiment-with-chatgpt-4&#34;&gt;An Experiment with ChatGPT-4&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-minute-read&#34;&gt;10 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the use of ChatGPT-4 to analyze and extract customer personas from real-life interview data. By using AI, researchers can save significant time by avoiding manual analysis of lengthy audio recordings. The quality is pretty good, but you need to pay attention to the overall accuracy of the output.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discovering and understanding customer personas is a common activity for businesses to create user-centered strategies and cater to the needs of their audience. In this article, I’ll explore an innovative approach to extracting personas using &lt;a href=&#34;https://chat.openai.com&#34;&gt;OpenAI’s ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt;, based on real-life interview data. The experiment aimed to evaluate the effectiveness of feeding raw data directly into the AI and observing the quality and relevance of the generated personas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Productivity: Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/evolving-productivity-getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/evolving-productivity-getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;evolving-productivity-getting-things-done&#34;&gt;Evolving Productivity: Getting Things Done&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-david-allens-productivity-system-changed-the-game-for-me&#34;&gt;How David Allen&amp;rsquo;s Productivity System Changed the Game for Me&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I dive deeper into personal productivity systems by exploring my transition from the Franklin Planner to David Allen&amp;rsquo;s Getting Things Done method, and how a combination of the two has helped me achieve greater success.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continuing our &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity&#34; title=&#34;drew:ux articles tagged #productivity&#34;&gt;discussion&lt;/a&gt; of personal productivity systems, we&amp;rsquo;ve already explored the Franklin Planner system and its connection to Benjamin Franklin&amp;rsquo;s methods. As we continue, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at another powerful productivity system: David Allen&amp;rsquo;s Getting Things Done (GTD) method. In this follow-up article, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experiences transitioning from the Franklin Planner to GTD, and how customizing a combination of both systems has helped me achieve greater productivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analog Days: Rediscovering the Franklin Planner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/analog-days-rediscovering-the-franklin-planner/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/analog-days-rediscovering-the-franklin-planner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;analog-days-rediscovering-the-franklin-planner&#34;&gt;Analog Days: Rediscovering the Franklin Planner&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploring-the-roots-of-the-franklin-planner-system-and-its-connection-to-benjamin-franklins-methods&#34;&gt;Exploring the roots of the Franklin Planner system and its connection to Benjamin Franklin’s methods&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dive into the history of the Franklin Planner system, a once-popular analog productivity tool, and learn how its principles are rooted in Benjamin Franklin’s methods for personal development and virtue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve always been a bit of a productivity system nerd. I’ve been fascinated by how others manage their lives, stay on top of tasks, and keep things organized. When I landed my first job out of college, I was sent to a Franklin Quest seminar where I received a vinyl-covered planner and was introduced to the world of personal and professional organization. Little did I know, it would spark a lifelong interest in productivity systems and tools.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lean UX: The Ultimate Framework for Integrating UX and Agile Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lean-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lean-ux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lean-ux-the-ultimate-framework-for-integrating-ux-and-agile-development&#34;&gt;Lean UX: The Ultimate Framework for Integrating UX and Agile Development&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;delve-into-the-lean-ux-methodology-its-components-and-real-world-success-stories&#34;&gt;Delve into the Lean UX methodology, its components, and real-world success stories&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discover how Lean UX bridges the gap between UX and Agile development, explore its components, and learn from real-world success stories and challenges in the era of remote work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always been passionate about finding ways to seamlessly integrate UX and Agile development, and the Lean UX methodology has proven to be an ideal solution. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive deeper into Lean UX, its components, and how it has been successfully adopted by real-world organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/front-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/front-matter/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Free Remote UX Tools to Boost Your Workflow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-free-remote-ux-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/five-free-remote-ux-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-free-remote-ux-tools-to-boost-your-workflow&#34;&gt;5 Free Remote UX Tools to Boost Your Workflow&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;discover-budget-friendly-solutions-for-remote-ux-research-and-collaboration&#34;&gt;Discover budget-friendly solutions for remote UX research and collaboration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;2 ½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hey there, fellow UX advocates! Working remotely can be challenging on its own, and even more difficult when you&amp;rsquo;re on a budget. Many of the most exciting and essential tools for conducting UX research and design come with heft monthly subscription costs. But don&amp;rsquo;t worry, I&amp;rsquo;ve got your back. I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a list of five free tools that can help you navigate the world of remote UX without breaking the bank. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in and explore these budget-friendly UX tools!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling UX and Agile Development: A Unified Approach</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/reconciling-ux-and-agile-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/reconciling-ux-and-agile-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;reconciling-ux-and-agile-development-a-unified-approach&#34;&gt;Reconciling UX and Agile Development: A Unified Approach&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;integrating-ux-design-into-the-agile-process-for-holistic-user-centric-product-development&#34;&gt;Integrating UX Design into the Agile Process for Holistic, User-Centric Product Development&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-minute-read&#34;&gt;3 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Discover how to reconcile UX and Agile development by integrating UX design into the Agile process for a holistic, user-centric product development approach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my second installment focused on UX and Agile. Agile development has long been known for its programmer-centric approach, which can sometimes leave UX feeling like a &amp;ldquo;side process.&amp;rdquo; However, I strongly believe that UX should be baked into the entire iterative process, much like QA validating dev work. UX validates design decisions and helps uncover user needs, driving product design. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to reconcile UX and Agile development by integrating UX design into the Agile process for a holistic, user-centric product development approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scrum, Kanban, and Scrumban: Integrating UX into Agile Methodologies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/scrum-kanban-scrumban-and-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/scrum-kanban-scrumban-and-ux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;scrum-kanban-and-scrumban-integrating-ux-into-agile-methodologies&#34;&gt;Scrum, Kanban, and Scrumban: Integrating UX into Agile Methodologies&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;explore-the-pros-and-cons-of-scrum-kanban-and-hybrid-approaches-for-ux-practitioners-in-the-agile-world&#34;&gt;Explore the pros and cons of Scrum, Kanban, and hybrid approaches for UX practitioners in the Agile world&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A handful of years back, I found myself participating in a Scrum-focused Agile training with the aim of earning certification. Coming from a UX background, I couldn’t help but be plagued by a persistent concern: how on earth does UX fit into all of this? So, on the final day of training, I posed the question to our instructor. He mulled it over for a moment before suggesting that UX is something you tackle at the very beginning of the process, and then you dive into Scrum. This didn’t seem very iterative or agile at all!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Business with Unicorns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-10-29-unicorns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-10-29-unicorns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;this-business-with-unicorns&#34;&gt;This Business with Unicorns&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-raccoon-a-panda-and-a-unicorn-walk-into-a-bar&#34;&gt;A Raccoon, a Panda, and a Unicorn walk into a bar&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-frac12--minute-read&#34;&gt;3 ½  minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paulolyslager.com/ux-full-stack-unicorn-and-how-it-was-born/&#34;&gt;Unicorns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: Mythical creatures that are spoken of, but never seen. In the UX world, the term is used to describe that rare person who can do it all — design, research, write, and code — and do it at a very high level. It&amp;rsquo;s become so common that companies looking for talent are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/227764042?trkInfo=searchKeywordString%3ADesign%2BUnicorn%2CsearchLocationString%3A%252C%2B%2Cvertical%3Ajobs%2CpageNum%3A1%2Cposition%3A6%2CMSRPsearchId%3A36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;refId=36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;recommendedFlavor=SCHOOL_RECRUIT&amp;amp;trk=jobs_jserp_job_listing_text&#34;&gt;putting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/202562884?trkInfo=searchKeywordString%3ADesign%2BUnicorn%2CsearchLocationString%3A%252C%2B%2Cvertical%3Ajobs%2CpageNum%3A1%2Cposition%3A7%2CMSRPsearchId%3A36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;refId=36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;trk=jobs_jserp_job_listing_text&#34;&gt;out&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/217005561?trkInfo=searchKeywordString%3ADesign%2BUnicorn%2CsearchLocationString%3A%252C%2B%2Cvertical%3Ajobs%2CpageNum%3A1%2Cposition%3A10%2CMSRPsearchId%3A36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;refId=36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;recommendedFlavor=COMPANY_RECRUIT&amp;amp;trk=jobs_jserp_job_listing_text&#34;&gt;job&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/view/208168879?trkInfo=searchKeywordString%3ADesign%2BUnicorn%2CsearchLocationString%3A%252C%2B%2Cvertical%3Ajobs%2CpageNum%3A1%2Cposition%3A13%2CMSRPsearchId%3A36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;refId=36420659_1477773649263&amp;amp;trk=jobs_jserp_job_listing_text&#34;&gt;ads&lt;/a&gt; for so-called &amp;ldquo;unicorns.&amp;rdquo; And well-known industry gurus are promising to show the path to single-hornedness &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uie.com/articles/becoming_a_unicorn/&#34;&gt;in five easy steps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnitude</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-10-16-magnitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-10-16-magnitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;magnitude&#34;&gt;Magnitude&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-simple-tool-to-help-prioritize-usability-issues&#34;&gt;A Simple Tool to Help Prioritize Usability Issues&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-minute-read&#34;&gt;6 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When prioritizing usability problems, use a &lt;strong&gt;Magnitude Matrix&lt;/strong&gt; to figure out the most important issues to address. Magnitude combines the frequency that an issue was observed with the relative impact that it had on the participant&amp;rsquo;s task completion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After spending some time revisiting best practices in the realm of usability testing and reviewing the advice of some its more esteemed practitioners, I realized that there is a lot of talk about how to go about setting up such a test, and finding usability problems. But there isn&amp;rsquo;t a whole lot said about what you do with them once you find them.&lt;a href=&#34;#caveat&#34; title=&#34;Actually, there is.&#34;&gt;*&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Playback</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-10-2-playback/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-10-2-playback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;playback&#34;&gt;Playback&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;often-the-best-way-to-fix-your-faults-is-to-look-directly-at-them&#34;&gt;Often the best way to fix your faults is to look directly at them&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-minute-read&#34;&gt;4 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Regularly reviewing your performance and providing self-critique can help you improve your skills as a usability test moderator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The camera and microphone are powerful implements in a usability tester&amp;rsquo;s toolkit. With them, you can capture the user&amp;rsquo;s actions and facial expressions and gain all kinds of insight into their behaviors, thoughts and expectations when using a product. But these tools can be equally useful in monitoring your own performance as a test moderator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reporting Qualitative Data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-24-reporting-qualitative-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-24-reporting-qualitative-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;reporting-qualitative-data&#34;&gt;Reporting Qualitative Data&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaining-control-of-the-fuzzy-non-numeric&#34;&gt;Gaining Control of the Fuzzy Non-Numeric&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-minute-read&#34;&gt;3 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When dealing with moderate to large sets of qualitative data, affinity analysis can help identify and prioritize common issues that users experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve spent a lot of time discussing quantitative data this week: Collecting, measuring, and analyzing it. This got me thinking about its more nebulous twin — qualitative data — and how it&amp;rsquo;s a whole different beast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eye-Tracking on the Cheap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-17-eye-tracking-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-17-eye-tracking-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;eye-tracking-on-the-cheap&#34;&gt;Eye-Tracking on the Cheap&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-dead-simple-way-to-follow-your-test-participants&#34;&gt;A Dead-Simple Way to Follow Your Test Participants&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-minute-read&#34;&gt;2 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the absence of eye-tracking equipment, ask test participants to use their mouse cursor to indicate where they’re looking on the screen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the hallmarks of usability testing protocols is [the “Think Aloud” method][1]: Asking participants to verbalize their thoughts as they work through the tasks and activities of the test. This method allows the test team to get inside the head of the participant a bit and often illuminates behaviors or attitudes that wouldn’t be apparent by observation alone. It’s a great tool that we employ in &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of our testing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formative vs. Summative Usability Studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-10-formative-summative-usability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-10-formative-summative-usability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;staying-ahead-of-the-wave&#34;&gt;Staying Ahead of the Wave&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;formative-vs-summative-usability-studies&#34;&gt;Formative vs. Summative Usability Studies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;2 ½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When looking at usability studies, you can generally lump them into two groups: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usabilitybok.org/formative-evaluation&#34;&gt;Formative studies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.usabilitybok.org/summative-evaluation&#34;&gt;summative studies&lt;/a&gt;. We&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about them this week and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a little bit about our approach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;formative-studies&#34;&gt;Formative Studies&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Formative studies, as the name implies, tend to happen at the beginning of the design process and are used to help guide the product in the right direction. They are a key part of the iterative design process, where you&amp;rsquo;re generating design ideas, testing them, and adjusting the design on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote UX Observation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-01-getting-out-of-the-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-09-01-getting-out-of-the-room/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;remote-ux-observation&#34;&gt;Remote UX Observation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-out-of-the-room-to-enhance-team-participation-in-ux&#34;&gt;Getting Out of the Room to Enhance Team Participation In UX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;4 ½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the major tenets we adhere to as a team is &lt;strong&gt;transparency&lt;/strong&gt;: All members of the team should have access to information about the project we’re working on. Designers, Developers, QA Analysts, Stakeholders: They all should have a complete picture of what’s going on and access to any details of the project that might help them gain product perspective and user insights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IxD Retrospective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-07-01-ixd-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-07-01-ixd-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;retrospective&#34;&gt;Retrospective&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-back-on-the-kent-state-interaction-design-class&#34;&gt;Looking back on the Kent State Interaction Design class&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-minute-read&#34;&gt;4 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So another course in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinedegrees.kent.edu/programs-courses/graduate/user-experience-design/&#34;&gt;Kent State University User Experience Design Masters program&lt;/a&gt; comes to an end and, as one of its requirements has been these weekly updates, I thought it would be a good idea to use the final one to look back on the class.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent the last seven weeks diving into &lt;strong&gt;Interaction Design&lt;/strong&gt;; looking into the design process for digital products from the user interface perspective. This was the first time that this particular course was offered (which I find surprising), with the Department Chair reaching out to students only a month or so beforehand to see if there was any interest in taking such a class. As you might expect, it was a little thrown-together and rough around the edges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organized</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-26-organized/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-26-organized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;organized&#34;&gt;Organized&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-extra-time-taken-to-arrange-your-work-is-a-true-sign-of-professionalism&#34;&gt;The extra time taken to arrange your work is a true sign of professionalism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;2½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Look. What your workspace looks like when you go home for the day is your business. It’s your space and you need to be comfortable and able to get stuff done. Maybe it’s a minimalist nirvana; clean and cool and white. Maybe it’s a nest of papers, books, half-empty soda cans… whatever works for you. But your &lt;em&gt;work&lt;/em&gt; should reflect a clean orderliness; an underlying structure that reflects the beauty of the surface design.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measure Twice, Cut Once</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-19-mobile-layouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-19-mobile-layouts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;measure-twice-cut-once&#34;&gt;Measure Twice, Cut Once&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;creating-a-reusable-layout-system-for-mobile&#34;&gt;Creating a reusable layout system for mobile&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;4 ½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, while slugging it out in the trenches this week, I sort of fell into an existential crisis with regards to the stuff I was putting on the screen for a mobile prototype. Panels, images, buttons, text fields&amp;hellip; the sizing and positioning of these things all suddenly seemed so arbitrary. How can you defend a design decision if you can&amp;rsquo;t explain why the thing on the screen looks like it does?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critique</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-12-critique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-12-critique/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;critique&#34;&gt;Critique&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-having-your-back-means-shooting-you-down&#34;&gt;When having your back means shooting you down&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-minute-read&#34;&gt;5 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a good team.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I know this not because my team is talented; not because they wield terrifying text editors and pixel manipulators with the deftness of a Mayo Clinic surgeon (although they most certainly do). I know this because they are good at critique.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They are able to look at something — a design, concept, prototype — with a critical eye. To communicate their thoughts and opinions honestly and without agenda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>InVision This</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-05-invision-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-06-05-invision-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;invision-this&#34;&gt;InVision This&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;much-more-than-fancy-screenshots&#34;&gt;Much more than fancy screenshots&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;2 ½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you’ve probably gathered if you’ve been following along, I spend a lot of time &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/omg-cms&#34;&gt;talking&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;know-your-tools&#34;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;fidelity&#34;&gt;tools&lt;/a&gt;. Too much, probably. Tools, after all, don’t make the craftsman. But, here I go again: After a couple of weeks using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.invisionapp.com/&#34; title=&#34;InVision.app&#34;&gt;InVision.app&lt;/a&gt; for a project of some complexity, I have to say. Wow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been aware of InVision for awhile, but always thought of it as a fancy presentation tool (which it is) and nothing more (which it isn’t). You do all the real design work in another tool like Sketch, Illustrator, or Photoshop, right? Well, yeah, but…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fidelity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-05-29-fidelity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-05-29-fidelity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;fidelity&#34;&gt;Fidelity&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;when-making-wireframes-aim-somewhere-between-hi-fi-and-lo-fi&#34;&gt;When making wireframes, aim somewhere between hi-fi and lo-fi&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-minute-read&#34;&gt;4 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We spent a lot of time this week discussing fidelity as it pertains to UX deliverables: Wireframes in this case. The traditional wisdom has always been that wireframes are quick and dirty interface representations, &lt;a href=&#34;http://theuxreview.co.uk/wireframes-beginners-guide/&#34;&gt;stripped of any visual design or branding elements&lt;/a&gt;. Their purpose is to &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@danritz/wireframes-a-good-communication-tool-a-poor-design-tool-1bc64b033962#.xbomavigp&#34;&gt;communicate the general layout and content of a page&lt;/a&gt; without getting too deep into the visual design. The thinking goes, &amp;ldquo;Any UX schmoe can throw down a wireframe and leave the work of making it look nice to the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; designers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-05-22-know-your-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2016-05-22-know-your-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;know-your-tools&#34;&gt;Know your tools&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;investing-time-creating-a-basic-toolkit-early-can-really-pay-off&#34;&gt;Investing time creating a basic toolkit early can really pay off&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-minute-read&#34;&gt;2 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Which design tools you use are far less important than how well you can use them. This became especially apparent after weeks of using a template I created for the last class. It was easy. The bugs were ironed out. It looked okay. It didn&amp;rsquo;t win me any points for creative vision but it was fast and got the job done. Most important, it removed a lot of guesswork from my writing assignments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UX Yin and Yang: Balancing Organizational Goals and the Needs of Your Users</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-08-ux-yin-yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-08-ux-yin-yang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;ux-yin-and-yang&#34;&gt;UX Yin and Yang&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;balancing-organizational-goals-and-the-needs-of-your-users&#34;&gt;Balancing Organizational Goals and the Needs of Your Users&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;4½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The disciplines of user-centered design have taught us to go to great lengths to ensure that we meet the needs of users when it comes to our products, but we shouldn’t be doing so at the expense of the organization’s goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Call it a lesson learned. Awhile back my buddy (whom I&amp;rsquo;ll call &amp;ldquo;Ted,&amp;rdquo; in an attempt to spare his identity) completed a project that he’d spent significant time designing and building. His team had gone to great lengths to make this Web-based application a user-centered winner: They’d researched, created detailed user personas, interviewed and observed real users in their native environments, prototyped their brains out, iterated. They had it all figured out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotable: The Best Thing for Being Sad</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-03-thought-of-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-03-thought-of-today/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-best-thing-for-being-sad&#34;&gt;The Best Thing for Being Sad&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-minute-read&#34;&gt;1 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“The best thing for being sad,” replied Merlin, beginning to puff and blow, “is to learn something. That’s the only thing that never fails. You may grow old and trembling in your anatomies, you may lie awake at night listening to the disorder of your veins, you may miss your only love, you may see the world about you devastated by evil lunatics, or know your honour trampled in the sewers of baser minds. There is only one thing for it then — to learn. Learn why the world wags and what wags it. That is the only thing which the mind can never exhaust, never alienate, never be tortured by, never fear or distrust, and never dream of regretting. Learning is the only thing for you. Look what a lot of things there are to learn.” - T.H. White&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting the Most Out of your CMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-01-omg-cms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-12-01-omg-cms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-the-most-out-of-your-cms&#34;&gt;Getting the Most Out of your CMS&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;4½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“We become what we behold. We shape our tools, and thereafter our tools shape us.” ― &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/455.Marshall_McLuhan&#34; title=&#34;Marshall McLuhan&#34;&gt;Marshall McLuhan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to deciding on a content management system for a business or organization, how much should you expect your CMS to do? Is the solution you choose going to be a magic bullet that automatically enforces policy and standards? Should it encapsulate your entire workflow? While vendors would certainly have you believe it, the real answer is a bit less ideal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them):  Part 2, Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-11-19-content-challenges-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-11-19-content-challenges-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-content-strategy-challenges-and-how-to-overcome-them&#34;&gt;Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-2challenges-for-management&#34;&gt;Part 2 — Challenges for Management&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;3½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last week I discussed the five most common content strategy challenges for content creators and strategists. Organizational leadership faces a similar predicament. With so much emphasis put on productivity, efficiency and the bottom line, it’s hard to embrace a concept that doesn’t show a clear benefit for the organization, introduces too much risk or just doesn’t fit in with their vision of the company and its values. If you’re a manager, or you’re trying to convince executives to embrace content strategy, these challenges are probably all-too-familiar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them):  Part 1, The Content Creator</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-11-10-content-challenges-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-11-10-content-challenges-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;five-content-strategy-challenges-and-how-to-overcome-them&#34;&gt;Five Content Strategy Challenges (and How to Overcome Them)&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1the-content-creator&#34;&gt;Part 1 — The Content Creator&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;3½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Content strategy is an important component of the design process and vital to the overall user experience. It ensures that the organization’s content aligns with its goals and values. With that in mind, here are ten key challenges that content creators and management face with content strategy, and some proposed solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges-for-content-creators&#34;&gt;Challenges for Content Creators&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Content creators and strategists have it rough. Slogging it out in the trenches, we often see first-hand some of the impediments that constantly threaten our productivity, the quality of our work, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyclaudiia.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/week-10-1-content-strategy.gif&#34;&gt;our sanity&lt;/a&gt;; often without the political clout or influence to effect a change. But it doesn’t have to be like this. Here are the top issues you’ve likely to encountered, and some practical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site Search: Using Google vs. Rolling-Your-Own</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-05-23-site-search-google-vs-roll-your-own/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2015-05-23-site-search-google-vs-roll-your-own/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;site-search-using-google-vs-rolling-your-own&#34;&gt;Site Search: Using Google vs. Rolling-Your-Own&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2frac12-minute-read&#34;&gt;2½ minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So. You’ve built a Web site and need local search capabilities. Is it even worth it to develop your own solution when Google offers the whole deal by copying-and-pasting a few lines of code? With Google being able to crawl and catalog the expanse of (almost) the entire Web and present search results quickly and clearly to users, it’s a legitimate question to ask: Do any sites really need their own search systems? While many sites can forgo a proprietary search and just rely on Google, there are still a few good arguments to made for proprietary site search.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UX Triple Constraint: Time, Complexity and the User Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014-06-25-the-ux-triple-constraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2014-06-25-the-ux-triple-constraint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-ux-triple-constraint&#34;&gt;The UX Triple-Constraint&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;time-complexity-and-the-user-experience&#34;&gt;Time, Complexity and the User Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-minute-read&#34;&gt;4 minute read&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Someone much smarter than I has probably already made this observation, but it occurred to me in a recent discussion with a product stakeholder that there exists a kind of “usability triple constraint,” not too different from the one folks in the project management world have recognized for years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_management_triangle&#34; title=&#34;The Project Management Triangle - Wikipedia&#34;&gt;triple constraint&lt;/a&gt; is a project management model that says that all projects are a balance of time, resources, and quality. Or, as the sign behind the counter at my auto mechanic puts it:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archive</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Meaningful Experiences | About Drew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;creating-meaningful-experiences&#34;&gt;Creating Meaningful Experiences&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-drew&#34;&gt;About Drew&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Drew Todd, a dedicated professional with over 20 years of experience in Internet, Web, and mobile application development. As a certified project manager, I bring my design and engineering expertise to my role as the Director of Web Development at a renowned AV manufacturer in Anaheim, CA, where I lead a talented team in creating award-winning digital products.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My passion lies in understanding and enhancing user experiences. This blog focuses on my insights into UX &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/research&#34; title=&#34;Articles tagged #research&#34;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/design&#34; title=&#34;Articles tagged #design&#34;&gt;design&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/accessibility&#34; title=&#34;Articles tagged #accessibility&#34;&gt;accessibility&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/ai&#34; title=&#34;Articles tagged #ai&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/agile&#34; title=&#34;Articles tagged #agile&#34;&gt;agile&lt;/a&gt; development, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity&#34; title=&#34;Articles tagged #productivity&#34;&gt;personal productivity&lt;/a&gt;, and how these elements contribute to creating exceptional digital products. By delving into the intricacies of user interaction and product design, I aim to empower businesses to meet their objectives while offering users delightful experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
